A Guide to the John Maynard Poythress genealogical notes, 1633-12012
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
John Maynard Poythress genealogical notes, 1633-12012
The Library of Virginia
52087
4.6 cu. ft. and 9 boxes
John Maynard Poythress
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Giff ot E. Dewayne and Leigh Wilson of Townsend, Tennessee
Biographical Information
Poythress, John Maynard (1934-2012) was born in Macon Georgia and graduated from Mercer University with a degree in English literature. He was a general manager at Inland Container where he worked for 36 years. He was married to Jean Knott Poythress for 54 years and they had children.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1633-2012, of John Maynard Poythress (1934-2012) of Louisville, Kentucky, consisting of Poythress family genealogical research material. Papers included family descendents of Francis Poythress (d. ca. 1650) who immigrated from England about 1633. Collection includes references to early colonial Virginia families, including Francis Poythress' daughter Jane who may have married Thomas Rolfe, so of John Rolfe and Pocahontas. Research includes material referencing family branches that settled initially in Charles City County and Prince George County, Virginia; and then later settling in Georgia, with some branches in Alabama and North Carolina. Additional material relating to the Prince George County plantation Flowerdew Hundred, owned by Joshua Poythress and his descendants from 1725 to 1949, is also included. Collection contains annotated books and copies of additional sources, such as wills, deeds, censuses, and military records. Correspondence from other Poythress researchers, and extensive genealogical research notes are also included.
Contents List
- Unentangled--Poythress family history (folder 1 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Unentangled--Poythress family history (folder 2 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Unentangled--Poythress family history (folder 3 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Unentangled--Poythress family history (folder 4 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Unentangled--Poythress family history (folder 5 of 5) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Poythress material--Barbara P. Neal (folder 1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Poythress material--Barbara P. Neal (folder 2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Poythress material--Barbara P. Neal (folder 3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Poythress material--from Bud Poythress (folder 1 of 6) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Poythress material--from Bud Poythress (folder 2 of 6) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Poythress material--from Bud Poythress (folder 3 of 6) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Poythress material--from Bud Poythress (folder 4 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Poythress material--from Bud Poythress (folder 5 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Poythress material--from Bud Poythress (folder 6 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Poythress material--Earl F. Poythress (folder 1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Poythress material--Earl F. Poythress (folder 2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Poythress material--from Bud Poythress (folder 3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Poythress material--from Craig R. Scott (folder 1 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Poythress material--from Craig R. Scott (folder 2 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Poythress material--from Craig R. Scott (folder 3 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Poythress material--from Craig R. Scott (folder 4 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Poythress material--from Craig R. Scott (folder 5 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Poythress material--from Craig R. Scott (folder 6 of 6) (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Poythress material--Barbara P. Wolfe (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Poythress material--Jean's Notes (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Poythress material--Fred Upchurch (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Poythress material-- Francis Poythress (volume 1) (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Poythress material-- Francis Poythress (volume 2) (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Poythress material-- Francis Poythress (volume 3) (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Virginia's Descendants-- Francis Poythress Family Report(folder 1 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Virginia's Descendants-- Francis Poythress Family Report(folder 2 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Virginia's Descendants-- Francis Poythress Family Report(folder 3 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Virginia's Descendants-- Francis Poythress Family Report(folder 4 of 4) (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Confederate Service Records--Poythress (Box 3, Folder 34)
- The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints--Poythress records (folder 1 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 35)
- The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints--Poythress records (folder 2 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 36)
- The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints--Poythress records (folder 3 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 37)
- The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints--Poythress records (folder 4 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 38)
- R. Bolling Batte Card File--Poythress records (folder 1 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 39)
- R. Bolling Batte Card File--Poythress records (folder 2 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 40)
- R. Bolling Batte Card File--Poythress records (folder 3 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 41)
- R. Bolling Batte Card File--Poythress records (folder 4 of 4) (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Flowerdew Hundred (folder 1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Flowerdew Hundred (folder 2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Virginia General--Volume 1 (Box 5, Folder 45)
- Virginia General--Volume 2 (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Virginia General--Volume 3 (Box 5, Folder 47)
- Virginia General--Volume 4 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Virginia General--Volume 5 (Box 5, Folder 49)
- Virginia General--Volume 6 (Box 5, Folder 50)
- Virginia General--Volume 7 (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Virginia General--Volume 8 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 52)
- Virginia General--Volume 8 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 53)
- Virginia General--Volume 8 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Virginia General--Volume 9 (Box 6, Folder 55)
- Virginia General--Volume 10 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 56)
- Virginia General--Volume 10 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 57)
- Virginia General--Volume 11 (Box 6, Folder 58)
- Virginia General--Volume 12 (Box 6, Folder 59)
- Georgia--Volume 1--Georgia censusus (folder 1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 60)
- Georgia--Volume 1--Georgia censusus (folder 2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 61)
- Georgia--Volume 2 (Box 7, Folder 62)
- Georgia--Volume 3--Georgia Archives microfilm material on Screven County (Box 7, Folder 63)
- Georgia--Volume 4 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 64)
- Georgia--Volume 4 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 65)
- Georgia--Volume 5 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 66)
- Georgia--Volume 5 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 67)
- Georgia--Volume 5 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 8, Folder 68)
- Georgia--Volume 6 (folder 1 of 4) (Box 8, Folder 69)
- Georgia--Volume 6 (folder 2 of 4) (Box 8, Folder 70)
- Georgia--Volume 6 (folder 3 of 4) (Box 8, Folder 71)
- Georgia--Volume 6 (folder 4 of 4) (Box 8, Folder 72)
- Great Britain (Box 8, Folder 73)
- Adventures of Purse and Person 1607-1624/5 and Their Families (Box 8, Folder 74)
- Virginia Genealogical Research Guide (Box 8, Folder 75)
- National Genealogical Society Quarterly volume 80, number 2 Research in Georgia (Box 8, Folder 76)
- Descendants of Francis Epes I of Virginia, volume two, compiled and edited by John Frederick Dorman (Box 8, Folder 77)
- Ancestors and Descendants of Francis Epes I of Virginia, volume one, John Frederick Dorman (Box 9)
- Virginia Colonial Abstracts, series 2, volume 6, Prince George County, VA Land Patents 1666-1719, Lindsay O. Duvall, abstractor adn compiler (Box 9)
- Early Virginia Families Along the James River, volume II, Charles City County-Prince George County, Louise Pledge Heath Foley, compiler (Box 9)
- Our All-Southern Family, Carolyn Barfield Fulghum (Box 9)
- A History of Burke County, Georgia 1777-1950, Albert M. Hillhouse (Box 9)
- Screven County History, Dixon Hollingsworth, editor (Box 9)
- Georgia, Bernice McCullar (Box 9)
- Georgia Genealogical Gems Special Publicantion No. 48, National Genealogical Society, Washington D.C. (Box 9)
- Brunswick County, Virginia 1720-1975, Gay Neale (Box 9)
- The Cradle of the Republic Jamestown and James River Virginia, Lyon Gardiner Tyler (Box 9)
- Prince George County Virginia Miscellany 1711-1814, Benjamin B. Weisiger III, abstractor and compiler (Box 9)
- Prince George County, Virginia Records 1733-1792 Abstracts of the Remaining County Record Books for the Above Period Plus Miscellaneous Wills, Benjamin B. Weisiger, abstractor and compiler (Box 9)
- Prince George County, Virginia Wills and Deeds 1710-1713, Benjamin B. Weisiger III, compiler (Box 9)